GURSHEEN CHAWLA, MCA

613-620-2378 • gursheen1436@gmail.com • Ottawa, ON K2V 0S3 • www.gursheen.dev/

IT PROFESSIONAL

Junior Web Developer with hands-on experience in developing the frontend or backend. 2+ years of background in technical support and client service within a B2B setting. Earned a certificate in Web Development and recently completed the Advanced Information and Cyber Security Leadership course at the University of Ottawa-PDI and Introduction to Python Programming from Southern Alberta Institute of Technology. Attended a 5-week practice firm training with Axiom. Working towards Scrum Certification.

- Demonstrates sound understanding and application of digital threats in web development.
- Successfully worked in agile environments.
- Figure 1. Effective verbal and written communication skills; speaks English, Punjabi, and Hindi.
- Advanced proficiency in MS Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, & Outlook), internet technologies, and social media platforms.

<u>Capstone Project (University of Ottawa – Professional Development Institute)</u>

Title: Attack Analysis on Ottawa's French School Cyber Attack 2021

Project Outcome: Designed an information and cyber security plan that focused on the 4 pillars of cyber security – *Security, Safety, Privacy, & Technology*.

Capstone Project (Code Youth)

Title: WordBook

Project Outcome: Developed a single-page application to search and bookmark words from free dictionary API. It uses the IndexedDB API and Asynchronous JavaScript to power the app.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sutherland (Canada)

May 2022 – Present

ESPN+ STREAMING SUPPORT

- Providing first-level support through inbound/outbound calls and chats using Salesforce.
- Responsible for technical troubleshooting, retention, and subscription issues.

Code Youth (Canada)

October 2021 – January 2022

VOLUNTEER RESEARCHER

- Researched the application and scope of frameworks and programming languages used in web development.
- Checked and analyzed different online websites that offer courses on web design and development, gaming, and mobile development.

(continued)

Agsoft Solutions Private Ltd. (India)

May 2018 - September 2020

SUPPORT SPECIALIST

- Represented the company in various sales and support-related activities and functions.
- Handled inbound calls from clients to provide first-level technical support; troubleshooted issues remotely based on service orders or customer accounts.
- Collaborated with supervisors via live chat to address customer inquiries or technical issues beyond scope of expertise but ensuring consistent compliance with company standards.
- Cultivated client relations and drove retention by effectively authoring and updating technical documentation and manuals.
- Documented and updated case notes for each client and work order based on established policies, procedures, and guidelines.

Dhilwan International Public School - DIPS (India)

March 2016 – October 2016

MATHEMATICS INSTRUCTOR

- Designed curriculum and developed lesson plans; instructed over 100 students per semester.
- Distributed and posted course syllabus and answered student questions regarding course standards, learning materials, grading system, and progression/evaluation at the beginning of the semester.
- Posted periodic grades and final grade rosters in the school grading system with supporting documents according to prescribed deadlines.
- Modified instructional methods and strategies to teach students with diverse needs and learning curves.

PRACTICE FIRM TRAINING

Axiom (Canada)

February 2022 – March 2022

(One of the leading strategic technology consulting companies that offer a comprehensive menu of services and technical solutions to support businesses across North America.)

Applied Information Technology and Security Student Trainee

- Applies knowledge and skills in information and cyber security in an actual work setting through a trainer-led virtual platform.
- Learns practical understanding and application of cyber security tasks, internal security audits, and penetration testing in business environments.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Master of Computer Applications

2015 -2017

Lovely Professional University / India

Bachelor of Computer Applications

2012 -2015

Guru Nanak Dev University / India

(continued)

Introduction to Python Programming

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology (online), Alberta | March 2022 – April 2022

Systems Security Professional Essential Labs

Learning Tree International, Ottawa | March 2022 – Present

Advanced Information and Cyber Security Leadership Certificate

University of Ottawa – Professional Development Institute (PDI), Ottawa | November 2021 – March 2022 *Core Courses:* Frameworks, 8 Bodies of Knowledge, Threats, SIEM, SIRT, TTX, Gap Analysis, Risk Register, ISO Standards, Privacy Applications, and Legal

Web Development Bootcamp

Code Youth, Ottawa | December 2021 – February 2022 Core Courses: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, API, DOM, Git and GitHub